bharathikannank05@gmail.com

+919443470347

Chennai, India

Bharathi Kannan V

Full Stack Developer

Excellent in developing applications from given business requirements and efficient in maintaining existing software.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer II

Photon Infotech 🗷

05/2020 - Present

Chennai

Roles and Responsibities

- Design and develop Single Page applications using Object-Oriented JavaScript, micro frameworks with responsive
- · Maintain code for existing web apps to support the latest devices.
- Utilize development skills to build and unit test app functionality per technical specifications.

Software Development Senior Analyst NTT Data GDS 🗷

11/2019 - 04/2020

Chennai

Roles and Responsibilities

- Involved in Developing Reusable components in ReactJs
- Involved in Testing the State Management library Redux

Programmer Analyst

Cognizant Technology Solutions &

04/2016 - 11/2019

Coimbatore

Roles and Responsibilities

· Requirements Analysis, Design, Implementation, Development and Testing of .Net Web application

PROJECTS

Project Management Dashboard (11/2019 - Present)

- A Data visualization application, which helps project managers to allocate and manage the team members in the projects.
- The React web application provides option for registered users to add new employee requests, categorize the requests based on the completion status, navigate and view the created entries either in a List View or Card View.

ASP.NET MVC Web Application (11/2017 - 05/2018)

- This Web Application is developed for business users, who use it as an interactive tool to effectively manage the business data as well as user data.
- Features: Spreadsheet Export from visualized data grid, Excel Upload, Displaying the uploaded excel in web page and providing user an option to edit the spreadsheet.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering

Sri Ramakrishna Engineering College

2012 - 2016

Coimbatore

Specialization

 Computer Science and Engineering

SKILLS

React JS Redux ASP.Net MVC JavaScript ES6/ES8 .NET Core Web API Mongo DB Node JS C# Microservices

ACHIEVEMENTS

Front-End Web Development with React (03/2020) Completed the course with 100% Grade provided by The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology through Coursera

Certified Full Stack Engineer (03/2019)

Provided by National Institute of Information Technology and Sponsored by Cognizant Technology Solutions

Pick of the Month (10/2019)

In the Quarterly Newsletter for the proposal and development of Value add for the web application, which significantly saves \$43,000 US dollars for the client per year

First Prize in Android Hackathon 2k15 (11/2015)

Conducted by HR Cube at Jansons Intitute of Technology, Coimbatore and awarded with Part-Time Internship at HR Cube, an US based IT company.

EXPERIENCE SUMMARY

Overall experience of 4.2 years in Web Application Development, Front End Development and Internet based Technologies

Good hands on exposure in React.JS, Redux, JavaScript, MongoDB, ASP.NET Core Web Services, Docker Containers, JSON (MERN Stack)

Good Project Level exposure in ASP.NET, C#, MVC 5.2, Kendo UI, JQuery, AJAX, SQL Server, OracleDB, MSBI -SSIS, HTML5, Bootstrap, CSS.

Good exposure in Third Party User Interface Libraries like Telerik Controls and Kendo UI for ASP MVC. ReactStrap and Material UI for React

LANGUAGES

English Tamil

INTERESTS

Phones Technology Android

Movies